Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we are going back in time.
今天我们要回到过去。
That's right, we're visiting the 1950s.
没错，我们要去1950年代。
Alright so we are going to the year 1950 and well, we are going to look at some of the
好的，所以我们要去1950年，我们要看看那个年代
typical and common words and phrases that were used back in that year.
常用的一些典型词汇和短语。
Yes, all of these words and phrases you might still hear today but they are really a little
是的，这些词汇和短语你今天可能还能听到，但它们确实有点
bit old-fashioned.
过时了。
Alright, so we have some words that we need to look at before we listen to our dialogue.
好的，在听对话之前，我们需要先看一些单词。
So let's look at these words in Vocabulary Preview.
那我们来看看词汇预览部分。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
We have two words we're going to hear in the dialogue.
我们有两个词会在对话中听到。
The first one, sock hop.
第一个是sock hop。
Sock hop.
Sock hop。
A sock hop.
一个sock hop。
Okay, now this is very old-fashioned and probably not used anymore.
好的，这非常过时，可能现在不再用了。
No, not used anymore.
对，不再用了。
But a sock hop is a school dance.
但sock hop指的是学校舞会。
Okay so all the kids after school would get together and dance rock and roll in the gym
好的，所以所有孩子放学后会聚在一起，在体育馆里跳摇滚舞
or something.
之类的。
And well, it's very popular and very common among American culture in those days.
嗯，这在当时的美国文化中非常流行和常见。
Yes, in 1950.
是的，在1950年。
So you would still maybe see this in a movie or something like that.
所以你也许还会在电影之类的地方看到它。
And our second word is still used today.
我们的第二个词今天还在用。
Sadie Hawkins dance.
Sadie Hawkins舞会。
A Sadie Hawkins dance.
一个Sadie Hawkins舞会。
Alright, a Sadie Hawkins dance.
好的，一个Sadie Hawkins舞会。
So a Sadie Hawkins dance is a dance when the girls ask the guys to be their date.
所以Sadie Hawkins舞会是指女孩邀请男孩做他们舞伴的舞会。
Okay, so it's a party and the guys don't invite the girls.
好的，所以这是一个派对，男孩不邀请女孩。
No, the girls invite the guys.
不，是女孩邀请男孩。
Okay, so it's a little bit of a reverse of roles there.
好的，所以角色有点反过来了。
Yes.
是的。
That's interesting.
这挺有意思的。
So in this case, the girls have to come up to the guys and say, hey, do you want to go
所以在这种情况下，女孩得走到男孩面前说，嘿，你想和我一起去
to the dance with me?
舞会吗？
Very good.
非常好。
Well, this still happens today in North America, so you will probably hear it sometime.
嗯，这在北美今天仍然会发生，所以你可能会在某个时候听到它。
And I guess now we could listen to a dialogue for the first time.
我想我们现在可以第一次听对话了。
And it takes place at a high school.
它发生在一所高中。
Hey, Tracy, how are you doing?
嘿，特蕾西，你怎么样？
I'm swell, Sandy.
我很好，桑迪。
Hey, listen, you want to go to the sock hop with me this Friday?
嘿，听着，这周五你想跟我一起去袜子舞会吗？
It'll be a blast.
那会很好玩的。
First of all, it's the Sadie Hawkins dance.
首先，那是萨迪·霍金斯舞会。
The girls got to ask the guys.
女生得邀请男生。
Also, all right.
还有，好吧。
So when are you going to ask me?
那你什么时候来邀请我？
I've had my eye on you for a while.
我注意你有一阵子了。
Hey, buddy, ease off my girl, man.
嘿，哥们，离我女朋友远点，伙计。
Or do you want a knuckle sandwich?
还是你想吃拳头三明治？
Cool it, guys.
冷静点，伙计们。
Your girl says who says me, pipsqueak.
你女朋友说谁说我，小不点。
All right, so a little bit of a discussion over a girl.
好吧，所以就是为个女孩有点争执。
Very common.
很常见。
Yes.
是的。
Yep.
嗯。
So we're going to be looking at some of these words that were maybe a little bit difficult
所以我们要看看对话中一些可能有点难的词，
in the dialogue in Language Takeaway.
在“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Well, we've got five phrases and words from the dialogue.
嗯，我们从对话中提取了五个短语和单词。
Now, the first thing we heard was Sandy said, heya.
首先，我们听到桑迪说“嘿呀”。
Heya.
嘿呀。
All right.
好的。
Now, an interjection, a way of saying hi, but very old-fashioned.
这是一个感叹词，一种打招呼的方式，但很老派。
Heya.
嘿呀。
Yep.
嗯。
Basically, hi, you.
基本上就是“嗨，你”。
Or hey, you.
或者“嘿，你”。
Yep.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
So heya.
所以是“嘿呀”。
I guess you would still use it today, though, right?
我猜你今天还会用这个词，对吧？
Yeah, it's still a normal way to greet someone.
是的，它仍然是一种正常的打招呼方式。
All right.
好的。
Very friendly.
非常友好。
Okay.
好的。
And what about our second word?
那第二个词呢？
Well, Sandy asks Tracy, how are you?
嗯，桑迪问特蕾西，“你好吗？”
And Tracy replies, I'm swell.
然后Tracy回答说：“我很好。”
I'm swell.
我很好。
Swell.
很好。
I'm just swell.
我很好。
When you are swell, you are great.
当你说“swell”时，意思是“你很好”。
You're great.
你很好。
And again, swell is an old-fashioned way of saying I'm good or I'm great, but you would
再说一次，“swell”是一种老式的说法，表示“我很好”或“我棒极了”，但你
still hear it.
仍然会听到它。
Yes.
是的。
And swell also is used to describe things.
“Swell”也可以用来描述事物。
That was a swell party.
那是个很棒的派对。
Okay.
好的。
Swell.
很好。
Yep.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
Now, for our next word, they got into a fight and Tracy said, cool it, guys.
现在，来看下一个词，他们吵了起来，Tracy说：“冷静点，伙计们。”
Cool it.
冷静点。
So, why don't we listen to some examples of cool it before we explain it.
所以，在我们解释之前，不如先听一些“cool it”的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
Just cool it.
冷静点。
Now is not the right time to get angry.
现在不是生气的时候。
Example two.
例子二。
You need to cool it and stop yelling at me.
你需要冷静下来，别对我大喊大叫。
Example three.
例子三。
Don't cry, Pam.
别哭了，Pam。
Just cool it.
冷静点。
You will be okay.
你会没事的。
All right.
好的。
So, cool it, guys.
所以，“冷静点，伙计们。”
Basically, it means...
基本上，它的意思是……
Relax.
放松。
Take it easy.
别紧张。
Yeah.
是的。
Don't get into a fight.
别打架。
Okay.
好的。
This is one my dad used to say to me and my sisters all the time.
这是我爸爸以前经常对我和我姐妹们说的话。
Cool it, kids.
孩子们，冷静点。
Stop fighting.
别打了。
Very good.
很好。
So, it is still very commonly used, I would say.
所以，我觉得它仍然很常用。
Yep.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
Now, for our last two words, these are a little bit more old-fashioned.
现在，最后两个词，这些有点过时了。
Yes.
是的。
Straight from 1952.
直接从1952年来的。
They talk about a knuckle sandwich.
他们说的是“指节三明治”。
All right.
好的。
He says, do you want a knuckle sandwich?
他说，你想要一个指节三明治吗？
A knuckle sandwich.
指节三明治。
What are we talking about here?
我们这是在说什么？
All right.
好的。
So, on your hand, you have...
所以，在你的手上，你有...
Above your fingers, you have your knuckles.
在你的手指上方，你有指节。
Okay.
好的。
So, those are the bumpy parts on my hand.
所以，那些是我手上凸起的部分。
Yeah.
嗯。
The bones on the top part of your hand.
你手背上的骨头。
So, he's basically saying, do you want me to punch you?
所以，他基本上是在说，你想让我揍你吗？
Right?
对吧？
Do you want me to hit you with my hand, with my fist?
你想让我用手、用拳头打你吗？
So, it's a very informal way of saying a punch, knuckle sandwich.
所以，这是一种非常非正式的说法，指节三明治就是一拳。
I'll give you a knuckle sandwich.
我会给你一个指节三明治。
Right.
对。
And for our last word, he called...
最后一个词，他叫...
Tommy called Sandy a pipsqueak.
汤米叫桑迪“小不点”。
A pipsqueak.
小不点。
Now, this is kind of an insult, but again, very old-fashioned.
这算是一种侮辱，但同样，非常过时。
Yes.
是的。
A pipsqueak is a very small person, right?
“小不点”指的是一个非常矮小的人，对吧？
A small person who is not strong.
一个不强壮的小个子。
Okay.
好的。
Or not powerful.
或者不强大。
So, a small and weak person.
所以，一个又小又弱的人。
Mm-hmm.
嗯哼。
Pipsqueak.
小不点。
I guess nowadays, you can still call somebody pipsqueak, but maybe in a lighter sense.
我猜现在你仍然可以叫某人“小不点”，但可能语气更轻松些。
It would be a little bit funny to call someone a pipsqueak.
叫别人“小不点”会有点好笑。
Okay.
好吧。
So, a pipsqueak.
所以，“小不点”。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again?
我们为什么不重新听一遍我们的对话呢？
We're going to slow it down a little bit so you can get all these words that we just looked
我们会稍微放慢速度，这样你就能听懂我们刚刚看过的所有单词，
at, and then we'll come back and look at some phrases.
然后我们再回来看看一些短语。
Hey Tracy, how are you doing?
嘿，特蕾西，你怎么样？
I'm swell, Sandy.
我很好，桑迪。
Hey, listen, you want to go to the sock hop with me this Friday?
嘿，听着，这周五你想和我一起去袜子舞会吗？
It'll be a blast.
那会很好玩的。
First of all, it's the Sadie Hawkins dance.
首先，那是萨迪·霍金斯舞会。
The girls got to ask the guys.
得由女孩邀请男孩。
Also...
还有……
Oh, right.
哦，对。
So, when are you going to ask me?
那你什么时候邀请我？
I've had my eye on you for a while.
我注意你有一阵子了。
Hey buddy, ease off my girl, man.
嘿，伙计，离我女朋友远点，老兄。
Or do you want a knuckle sandwich?
还是你想吃拳头三明治？
Cool it, guys.
冷静点，伙计们。
Your girl?
你女朋友？
Says who?
谁说的？
Says me, pipsqueak.
我说的，小不点。
Okay.
好吧。
So that was a little bit easier to understand, but some great 50s style phrases and words.
所以那更容易理解了，但有一些很棒的50年代风格的短语和单词。
So why don't we look at some of these phrases now in Fluency Builder.
那我们为什么不现在在流利度构建器里看看这些短语呢。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
All right.
好的。
On Fluency Builder today, we're going to look at three phrases.
在今天的流利度构建器中，我们要看三个短语。
Why don't we start with the first one?
我们为什么不从第一个开始呢？
Sandy said that the party will be a blast.
桑迪说派对会很好玩。
It'll be a blast.
那会很好玩的。
To be a blast.
很好玩。
So if something is a blast, it's very fun.
所以如果某件事很好玩，那就是非常有趣。
It's entertaining.
它很娱乐。
Yes.
是的。
Really, really fun.
真的，真的很有趣。
Okay.
好吧。
So the party was a blast.
所以派对很好玩。
I had a great time last night.
我昨晚玩得很开心。
It was a blast.
太棒了。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So, very fun times.
所以，非常有趣的时光。
Yep.
是的。
And you'll still hear this phrase used today.
而且你今天仍然会听到这个短语被使用。
Now, the next one.
现在，下一个。
So Sandy said he had his eye on Tracy.
所以桑迪说他一直盯着特蕾西。
He said, I've had my eye on you.
他说，我一直在关注你。
To have your eye on someone.
关注某人。
So if I have my eye on the new iPhone that came out.
所以如果我盯上了新出的iPhone。
You are watching it carefully because you want it.
你会仔细盯着它，因为你想要它。
Okay.
好的。
So I'm keeping my attention on it because I want it.
所以我一直把注意力放在它上面，因为我想要它。
I have my eye on that sweater because it's on sale.
我盯上了那件毛衣，因为它在打折。
Okay.
好的。
So you really want that sweater.
所以你真的很想要那件毛衣。
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好的。
So to have your eye on something or on someone.
所以，盯上某物或某人。
Right.
对。
So for our last phrase, Tommy told Sandy, hey buddy, ease off my girl.
所以对于我们的最后一个短语，汤米对桑迪说，嘿，哥们，离我女朋友远点。
Ease off.
放松点。
All right.
好的。
So why don't we listen to some examples of how we could use ease off because it might
所以我们不如听一些例子，看看我们怎么使用“ease off”，因为它可能
be a little bit tricky and then we'll come back and talk about it.
有点棘手，然后我们再回来讨论。
Example one.
例子一。
You need to ease off the junk food.
你需要少吃点垃圾食品。
Example two.
例子二。
Matt is putting so much pressure on me these days.
马特这些天给我施加了太多压力。
I wish he would ease off.
我希望他能放松点。
Example three.
例子三。
You're pushing Susie too much.
你对苏西逼得太紧了。
You need to ease off a bit.
你需要稍微放松一点。
Okay.
好的。
So it looks like you say this phrase ease off when somebody is putting pressure on you
所以看起来当有人给你施加压力
or doing something to you that they shouldn't.
或对你做不该做的事时，你会说这个短语“ease off”。
Right.
对。
Maybe they're being too intense or maybe annoying you.
也许他们太激烈了，或者惹恼了你。
So you tell them, hey, ease off.
所以你就告诉他们，嘿，放松点。
Relax.
放松。
Stay back.
退后。
Stay away.
离远点。
Very good.
很好。
So ease off.
所以放松点。
Ease off my girlfriend.
离我女朋友远点。
Ease off the fatty foods.
少吃油腻食物。
All right.
好的。
So take it easy.
所以放轻松。
Stay away from.
远离。
Yep.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So some great phrases there.
所以这里有一些很棒的短语。
I think it's a good idea for us to listen to our dialogue one more time and then we'll
我认为我们再听一遍对话是个好主意，然后我们会
come back and talk a little bit more about the 1950s.
回来再聊聊50年代。
Hey Tracy, how are you doing?
嘿，特蕾西，你好吗？
I'm swell, Sandy.
我很好，桑迪。
Hey, listen, you want to go to the sock hop with me this Friday?
嘿，听着，这周五你想和我一起去袜子舞会吗？
It'll be a blast.
会很好玩的。
First of all, it's the Sadie Hawkins dance.
首先，这是萨迪·霍金斯舞会。
The girls got to ask the guys.
女孩得邀请男孩。
Also.
还有。
Oh, right.
哦，对。
So when are you going to ask me?
那你什么时候邀请我？
I've had my eye on you for a while.
我已经关注你一段时间了。
Hey, buddy, ease off my girl, man.
嘿，哥们，离我女朋友远点，老兄。
Or do you want a knuckle sandwich?
还是你想吃拳头三明治？
Cool it, guys.
冷静点，伙计们。
Your girl?
你的女朋友？
Says who?
谁说的？
Says me, pipsqueak.
我说的，小不点。
Okay.
好的。
So the 1950s, a nice era.
所以50年代，一个不错的时代。
And this is the first of a small series that we're going to have of different words and
这是我们即将推出的一系列不同词汇和短语中的第一个，
phrases that were used back in the 1950s, 1960s, 1970s, et cetera.
这些词汇和短语在50年代、60年代、70年代等时期被使用。
That's right.
没错。
And a lot more time travel is coming up here in EnglishPod.
在EnglishPod里还会有更多的时间旅行内容。
Exactly.
正是。
Because a lot of these phrases are still used and you might even see them in movies or if
因为很多这些短语仍然被使用，你甚至可能在电影里看到它们，或者如果你
you're talking to somebody that was maybe born in these eras, they might even still
和那些可能出生在这些时代的人聊天，他们可能今天还在
use them today.
使用它们。
That's right.
没错。
So do you guys know any English phrases or slangs from the 1950s?
那么你们知道任何来自50年代的英语短语或俚语吗？
Why don't you visit our website at EnglishPod.com to tell us about it?
为什么不去我们的网站EnglishPod.com告诉我们呢？
All right.
好的。
We'll see you guys there and also if you have questions or comments, please leave them on
我们会在那里见到你们，如果你们有问题或评论，也请把它们留在
the comments section as well.
评论区。
Well thanks for listening and until next time.
感谢收听，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
EnglishPods.com